Guide to the John Burroughs Papers, 1850-1991 (bulk 1860-1921)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. WRITINGS: JOURNALS AND NOTEBOOKS, circa 1858-1921
  - Transcript of the Journals, with Annotations by Elizabeth Burroughs Kelley
    - Entries for 2 May 1887 - 10 July 1889, pp. 469-517, (TS, 50 p.) (Folder 7.10)
    - Entries for 12 July 1889 - 4 Nov 1891, pp. 518-566, (TS, 50 p.) (Folder 8.1)
    - Entries for 6 Nov 1891 - 31 May 1894, pp. 567-616, (TS, 51 p.) (Folder 8.2)
    - Entries for 1 June 1894 - 14 Apr 1897, pp. 617-667, (TS, 51 p.) (Folder 8.3)
    - Entries for 15 Apr 1897 - 31 Dec 1899, pp. 668-720, (TS, 54 p.) (Folder 8.4)
    - Entries for 1 Jan 1900 - 31 Dec 1902, pp. 721-769, (TS, 50 p.) (Folder 8.5)
    - Entries for 1 Jan 1903 - 2 Apr 1907, pp. 770-815, (TS, 46 p.) (Folder 8.6)
    - Entries for 3 Apr 1907 - 31 May 1910, pp. 816-865, (TS, 50 p.) (Folder 8.7)
    - Entries for 1 June 1910 - 31 Dec 1912, pp. 866-915, (TS, 50 p.) (Folder 8.8)
    - Entries for 1 Jan 1913 - 6 Jan 1916, pp. 916-961, (TS, 47 p.) (Folder 9.1)
    - Entries for 7 Jan 1916 - 4 Sep 1917, pp. 962-1013, (TS, 52 p.) (Folder 9.2)
    - Entries for 6 Sep 1917 - 2 July 1919, pp. 1014-1060, (TS, 52 p.) (Folder 9.3)
    - Entries for 3 July 1919 - 4 Feb 1921, pp. 1061-1102, (TS, 54 p.) (Folder 9.4)
  - Sketchbooks/Scrapbooks
    - Notebook of pencil sketches and clippings kept while traveling in New Jersey, with photocopied annotation by E.B.K., circa 1859 (Folder 64.1)
    - Notebook of pencil sketches and clippings from Saturday Press, of some of first articles J.B. wrote, but published under pen name, circa 1858 (Folder 64.2)
- SERIES II. WRITINGS: MANUSCRIPTS, circa 1850-1920
  - Afoot and Afloat — "John Burroughs: A Biography,", 1907; (galley proof) (Folder 64.16)
  - Afoot and Afloat — "A Summer Boating Trip,", 1907; (galley proof, incomplete) (Folder 64.16)
  - Afoot and Afloat — "A Tramp in the Catskills,", 1907; (galley proof, incomplete) (Folder 64.16)
  - "The Art of Home-making,", undated; (AMsS, 9 p.) (Folder 9.5)
  - "The Art of Home-making" — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (ANS, 1 p.) (Folder 9.5)
  - "Bird Life in an Old Apple Tree,", undated; (AMsS, 12 p.) (Folder 63.75)
  - Breath of Life — fragments not used in finished article known as "The Life Within Us,", undated; (AMs, 22 p.) (Folder 9.6)
  - "Camping with President Roosevelt," Atlantic Monthly, May 1906; (galley proof) (Folder 65.4 (Oversize))
  - "A Clever Beastie," Youth's Companion, [1917]; (TsS, 10 p., with 2 accompanying letters, an AMs frag, and a receipt for the poem, "Hepatica") (Folder 63.76)
  - "A Critical Glance into Thoreau," Atlantic Monthly, June 1919; (galley proof) (Folder 65.8 (Oversize))
  - "Eye-Beams," Riverby, 1894 — See "Field Notes," Century, June 1894
  - "Field Notes," Century, June 1894; (galley proof) (Folder 64.17)
  - "A Glance into Emerson's Journals," Art World, Nov 1917; (galley proof) (Folder 65.7 (Oversize))
  - "In the Heart of the Southern Catskills," Century, Aug 1888; (galley proof) (Folder 64.18)
  - "In the Noon of Science," The Atlantic, Sep 1912; (ms fragment) (Folder 63.80)
  - "The Journeying Atoms," Yale Review, Apr 1915; (galley proof) (Folder 65.6 (Oversize))
  - The Light of Day — "Science and Theology,", 1900; (AMsS, 94 p.) (Folder 9.7)
  - The Light of Day — Wrapper for above, labeled "From the Naturalists Point of View: Religious Discussions and Criticisms,", 1900; (AMsS, 1 leaf) (Folder 9.7)
  - The Light of Day — "Science and Theology Again,", undated; (AMs, fragment, 31 p.) (Folder 9.8)
  - The Light of Day — Sections IV and V, undated; (Ms, fragment, 10 p.) (Folder 9.9)
  - The Light of Day — "The Old Insoluable [sic] Problem,", undated; (AMs, fragment, 26 p.) (Folder 9.10)
  - The Light of Day — "The Fallacy of Professor Drummond's Natural Law in the Spiritual World,", undated; (AMs, 10 p.) (Folder 9.11)
  - The Light of Day — "Religious Discussions,", undated; (AMs, 10 p.) (Folder 9.12)
  - "Literary Values," Century, Apr 1902; (galley proof, set 1) (Folder 64.19)
  - "Literary Values," Century, Apr 1902; (galley proof, set 2) (Folder 64.20)
  - Literary Values — "Recent Phases of Literary Criticism,", 1902; (galley proof, incomplete, 1 p.) (Folder 65.2 (Oversize))
  - Literary Values — "Nature in Literature,", 1902; (galley proof, incomplete, 3 p.) (Folder 65.2 (Oversize))
  - "Gay Plumes and Dull," Leaf and Tendril, circa 18 Jan 1908; (galley proof) (Folder 9.13)
  - "How They Did It,", undated; (AMs, fragment, 12 p.) (Folder 9.14)
  - "A Lost February,", undated; (TMs, 27 p.) (Folder 9.15)
  - "Love and War Among the Blue Birds,", 16 Apr [no year]; (AMsS, 14 p.) (Folder 10.1)
  - "Love and War Among the Blue Birds" — note to Clara Barrus, undated; (ANS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.1)
  - "A Malformed Giant,", undated; (AMs, fragment, 13 p.) (Folder 10.2)
  - "A Malformed Giant" — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (ANS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.2)
  - "Midsummer Idyl," Harper's, Aug 1920; (galley proof, 2 copies) (Folder 65.9 (Oversize))
  - "Mr. Roberts' Red Fox,", undated; (AMsS, 20 p.) (Folder 10.3)
  - "Mr. Horneday's Wolverine,", undated; (AMsS, 10 p.) (Folder 10.3)
  - Note to "Mr. Whitney" regarding "Mr. Horneday's Wolverine" and "Mr. Roberts' Red Red Fox,", Jan 31, [no year]; (ALS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.3)
  - Untitled Ms that begins "The most wonderful thing about the dog is...", undated; (photocopy, 5 p.) (Folder 10.4)
  - Untitled Ms that begins "The most wonderful thing about the dog is..." — transcript by EBK, undated; (AMs, 4 p.) (Folder 10.4)
  - My Boyhood — note from EBK, undated; (photocopy, 1 p.) (Folder 10.5)
  - My Boyhood — folder 1 of 4, undated; (AMs, 33 p.) (Folder 10.5)
  - My Boyhood — folder 2 of 4, undated; (AMs, 53 p.) (Folder 10.6)
  - My Boyhood — folder 3 of 4, undated; (AMs, 47 p.) (Folder 10.7)
  - My Boyhood — folder 4 of 4, undated; (AMs, 38 p.) (Folder 10.8)
  - My Boyhood? — partial transcript typed by Julian Burroughs, folder 1 of 2 (Folder 51.5)
  - My Boyhood? — partial transcript typed by Julian Burroughs, folder 2 of 2 (Folder 51.6)
  - "New Gleanings in Old Fields," Far and Near, 1904; (galley proof, incomplete, includes 2 pages of written notes) (Folder 65.5 (Oversize))
  - "Notes on the Philosophy of the Hard Times,", undated; (AMsS, 42 p.) (Folder 10.9)
  - "Notes on the Philosophy of the Hard Times" — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (AMs, 1 p.) (Folder 10.9)
  - "Plea for a Simple Life,", undated; (AMs, fragment, 17 p.) (Folder 10.10)
  - "Real and Sham Natural History," Atlantic Monthly, March 1903; (galley proof, 2 copies) (Folder 65.3 (Oversize))
  - "A Sheaf of Nature Notes," The North American Review, Sep 1920; (galley proof) (Folder 65.10 (Oversize))
  - Signs and Seasons, selected passage, 1887 Sep 29; (AMsS, 1 p.) (Folder 67.23)
  - "Stories and Orbs,", undated; (TMs, fragment, 19 p.) (Folder 10.11)
  - "Strawberries,", undated; (AMsS) (Folder 10.12)
  - "Theory and Practice,", circa 1858-1862; (AMs, fragment, 1 p.) (Folder 10.13)
  - "Theory and Practice" — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (ANS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.13)
  - "The Victor Hugo Question,", undated; (AMsS, 34 p.) (Folder 10.14)
  - "The Victor Hugo Question" — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (ANS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.14)
  - "Waiting,", 5 June 1905; (AMsS, framed with photograph of Burroughs) (Box 64)
  - "Waiting,", 31 Mar 1908; (Holograph MS, in ink, on cardboard signed and dated. Original circa 14"x9", broken into two pieces) (Folder 10.15)
  - JB's introduction to Wasps, Social and Solitary, by George and Elizabeth Peckham, 1905; (AMs, 29 p. [AN, 1 p.]) (Folder 10.16)
  - Note to JB from Houghton Mifflin regarding his introduction to Wasps, Social and Solitary, 30 Jan 1905; (TLS, 1 p.) (Folder 10.16)
  - Sketch of a fireplace and chimney by JB, 1 June 1917 (Folder 10.16)
  - J.B.'s notes on trip to Yellowstone with Theodore Roosevelt, undated; (AMs, encapsulated, 11 p.) (Folder 10.17)
  - J.B.'s notes on Yellowstone trip — Transcription by Elizabeth Burroughs Kelley, undated; (photocopy, 6 p.) (Folder 10.17)
  - J.B.'s notes on Yellowstone trip — Transcription by Farida Wiley, undated; (AMs, encapsulated, 9 p.) (Folder 10.17)
  - J.B.'s notes on Yellowstone trip — Note on Farida Wiley's transcription by E.B.K., undated; (photocopy, 1 p.) (Folder 10.17)
  - Criticism of Benjamin Kidd's book, Social Evolution, [circa 1895]; (AMs, 29 p.) (Folder 10.18)
  - Criticism of Benjamin Kidd's book, Social Evolution — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (AN 1 p.) (Folder 10.18)
  - Fragments of very early manuscripts, [circa 1850]; (AMs, 47 leaves) (Folder 10.19)
  - Fragments of very early manuscripts — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (Photocopy, 1 p.) (Folder 10.19)
  - Untitled work on art written on Treasury stationary — fragment, circa 1863-1872; (AMs, 9 p.) (Folder 11.1)
  - Untitled work on art written on Treasury stationary — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (AN, 1 p.) (Folder 11.1)
  - Untitled talk given before a women's club in Massachusetts, [circa 1895]; (AMs, 11 p.) (Folder 11.2)
  - Untitled talk given before women's club — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (AN, 1 p.) (Folder 11.2)
  - Manuscript written by J.B. after learning of his wife's death, [9 May 1917]; (AMs, 6 p.) (Folder 11.3)
  - Manuscript written by J.B. after learning of his wife's death — note from Clara Barrus, [9 May 1917]; (AN 1 p.) (Folder 11.3)
  - Untitled article on economics — fragment, undated; (AMs, 15 p.) (Folder 11.4)
  - Untitled article on economics — note from Clara Barrus, undated; (AN, 1 p.) (Folder 11.4)
  - Fragments of miscellaneous manuscripts, undated; (AMs, 14 p.) (Folder 11.5)
  - Fragments (Folder 51.7)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS: PUBLISHED VERSIONS, 1859-1920
  - "Expression," Atlantic Monthly, Nov 1860 (Folder 63.64)
  - "With the Birds," Atlantic Monthly, May 1865; (photocopy) (Folder 62.1)
  - "Walt Whitman and his 'Drum Taps,'"Galaxy, 1 Dec 1866; (photocopy) (Folder 62.2)
  - "Speckled Trout," Atlantic Monthly, undated; (photocopy) (Folder 62.3)
  - "Eating Gravel,", 18 May 1872; (photocopy) (Folder 62.4)
  - "From London to New York," Galaxy, Feb 1873; (photocopy) (Folder 62.5)
  - "J.T. Trowbridge," Scribner's, Nov 1874; (photocopy) (Folder 62.6)
  - "House-Building," Scribner's, Jan 1876; (photocopy with EBK annotated) (Folder 62.7)
  - "A Word or Two on Emerson," Galaxy, Feb 1876; (photocopy) (Folder 62.8)
  - "What Makes the Poet," Galaxy, July 1876; (photocopy and annotated fragment) (Folder 62.9)
  - "A London Adventure," Scribner's, May 1877; (photocopy) (Folder 62.10)
  - "Off for Boyland,", 25 Dec 1879; (news clipping - by Burroughs?) (Folder 62.11)
  - "Henry D. Thoreau," Century, July 1882; (photocopy) (Folder 62.12)
  - "Carlyle," Century, Aug 1883; (photocopy) (Folder 62.13)
  - "Nature in England," Century, Nov 1883; (photocopy) (Folder 62.14)
  - "Birds' Eggs," Century, June 1886; (photocopy) (Folder 62.15)
  - "Lovers of Nature," The Chautauquan, May 1889; (with JB's editorial notes) (Folder 62.16)
  - "Fruit-Loving Birds," The Independent, 14 Feb 1891 (Folder 64.12)
  - "Short Discussions and Criticisms," The Open Court, 19 Mar 1891 (Folder 64.13)
  - "The Beneficial Aspect of Certain Errors," The Open Court, 10 Sep 1891 (Folder 64.13)
  - "Points of View," The Open Court, 24 Dec 1891 (Folder 64.13)
  - "Religious Truth," The Open Court, 21 July 1892 (Folder 64.13)
  - "A Young Marsh Hawk," St. Nicholas, Nov 1892 (Folder 62.17)
  - Introduction to Gilbert White's Natural History of Selburne, 1895 (Folder 62.18)
  - "A Bird's Free Lunch,", 1895 (Folder 62.19)
  - "The Porcupine," St. Nicholas, May 1896 (Folder 62.20)
  - "Style and 'the Stylist'," The Critic, Dec 1898 (Folder 64.13)
  - "In Warbler Time," Bird Lore, Feb 1899; (photocopy and reprint) (Folder 62.21)
  - "Glimpses of Wild Life About My Cabin," Century, Aug 1899 (Folder 62.22)
  - "Criticism and the Many," Atlantic Monthly, Sep 1899; (photocopy) (Folder 62.23)
  - "A Bird Talk," St. Nicholas, Nov 1899 (Folder 62.24)
  - "The Golden-Crown Sparrow of Alaska," Century, Nov 1899; (photocopy) (Folder 62.25)
  - "Summer Holidays in Alaskan Waters," Century, Aug 1900 (Folder 62.26)
  - "A Bewildered Phoebe," Bird Lore, June 1901 (Folder 62.27)
  - "Outdoor Poems," Atlantic Monthly, July 1901; (photocopy) (Folder 62.28)
  - "August Days," Harper's Monthly, Aug 1901 (Folder 62.29)
  - "Babes in the Woods," Harper's Monthly, Oct 1901 (Folder 62.30)
  - " A Spray of Arbutus," Outlook, 3 May 1902 (Folder 62.31)
  - "Literary Values," Century, Apr 1902; (2 copies) (Folder 62.32)
  - "Real and Sham Natural History," Atlantic Monthly, March 1903; (2 copies) (Folder 62.33)
  - "Early Spring Gladness," Century, March 1903; (photocopy) (Folder 62.34)
  - Animal Individuality," The Independent, 14 Jan 1904 (Folder 62.35)
  - "Do Animals Think?," Harper's, Feb 1905; (photocopy) (Folder 62.36)
  - "Are Animals Sympathetic?," Outing, May 1905; (photocopy) (Folder 62.37)
  - "In May," Country Calendar, May 1905 (Folder 64.14)
  - "Gay Plumes and Dull," Atlantic Monthly, June 1905; (fragment) (Folder 62.38)
  - "Camping with President Roosevelt," Atlantic Monthly, May 1906 (Folder 62.39)
  - "Corrupting the Innocents," The Independent, 19 Dec 1906 (Folder 62.40)
  - "Fake Natural History," Outing, Feb 1907 (Folder 62.41)
  - "Imagination in Natural History," Outlook, 29 June 1907 (Folder 62.42)
  - "President Roosevelt as a Nature Lover and Observer," Outlook, 13 July 1907 (Folder 62.43)
  - "Nature and Animal Life," Atlantic Monthly, Aug 1907 (Folder 62.44)
  - "The Reasonable but Unreasoning Animal," Outlook, 14 Dec 1907 (Folder 62.45)
  - "Mother Earth," Putnam's Magazine, Mar 1908 (Folder 62.46)
  - "Der Apfel" (The Apple), Montagsblatt, 12 Oct 1908; (includes letter from the editor) (Folder 56.14)
  - "The Divine Soil," Atlantic Monthly, Apr 1908 (Folder 62.47)
  - "Holidays in Hawaii," Century, Sep 1912 (Folder 62.48)
  - "Breath of Life," Atlantic Monthly, Apr 1913; (photocopy) (Folder 62.49)
  - "The Friendly Rocks," Harper's, Nov 1913; (photocopy) (Folder 62.50)
  - "Life as the Scientist Sees It," Yale Review, Oct 1914; (photocopy) (Folder 62.51)
  - "Life and Mind," North American Review, Oct 1914 (Folder 62.52)
  - "Dame Nature and her Children" The Companion, 18 Mar 1915 (Folder 64.14)
  - "A Bit of Natural History," Harper's Monthly, Feb 1916 (Folder 62.53)
  - "Life the Traveler," North American Review, Mar 1916 (Folder 62.54)
  - "The Master Instinct," Harper's Monthly, Mar 1916; (photocopy) (Folder 62.55)
  - "The Still Small Voice," Atlantic Monthly, Mar 1916 (Folder 62.56)
  - "Natura in Minimus Existat," The Art World, Jan 1917 (Folder 64.14)
  - "Stories from Burroughs," adapted by Clara Barrus, Schoolmate, Sep 1917; (photocopy) (Folder 62.57)
  - "Can Peace Make Us Forget," New York Tribune, 14 Dec 1917 (Folder 62.58)
  - "The Singing Birds," Harper's Monthly, May 1918 (Folder 62.59)
  - "A Clever Beastie," The Companion, 19 Sep 1918 (Folder 65.11 (Oversize))
  - "Shall We Accept the Universe?," North American Review, Jan 1919; (2 copies) (Folder 62.60)
  - "Theodore Roosevelt," Natural History, Jan 1919; (photocopy) (Folder 62.61)
  - "The Faith of a Naturalist," North American Review, Nov 1919 (Folder 62.62)
  - "Length of Days," Forecast, Sep 1919 (Folder 62.63)
  - "Length of Days," Dearborn Independent, 26 June 1920 (Folder 64.15)
  - "The Unapproachable Rainbow," Atlantic Monthly, July 1920; (photocopy) (Folder 62.64)
  - "Unapproachable Rainbow," Atlantic Monthly, July 1920; (EBK transcript) (Folder 62.65)
  - "A Midsummer Idyl," Harper's, Aug 1920; (photocopy) (Folder 62.66)
  - "What Makes a Poem," Bookman, Oct 1920 (Folder 62.67)
  - "Bald Heads and Headgear," Dearborn Independent, 8 Jan 1921 (Folder 62.68)
  - "The Reds of American Literature," Current Opinion, Apr 1921 (Folder 62.69)
  - "With Roosevelt at Pine Knot," Outlook, 25 May 1921; (2 copies) (Folder 62.70)
  - "My Life on the Farm," Country Life, May 1921 (Folder 64.14)
  - "New Gleanings in Field and Wood," Harper's Monthly, Aug 1921 (Folder 62.71)
  - "The Falling Leaves," Outlook, 2 Nov 1921 (Folder 62.72)
  - "My Boyhood, Part II," Harper's, Feb 1922; (photocopy) (Folder 62.73)
  - "Bird Life in Winter,", undated (Folder 62.74)
  - "Finding Two Bird's Nest,", undated (Folder 62.75)
  - "Hasty Observation,", undated (Folder 62.76)
  - "Notes of a Naturalist,", undated (Folder 62.77)
  - "The Robin,", undated (Folder 62.78)
  - "Thou Shall Not Preach,", undated (Folder 62.79)
  - "Waiting" [poem], undated (Folder 62.80)
  - Fragments (Folder 62.81)
  - "Exploring the Delaware" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.82)
  - "Bird Neighbors at Slabsides" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.83)
  - "Slide Mountain" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.84)
  - "A Barn-Door Outlook" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.85)
  - "The Art of Seeing Things" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.86)
  - "The Wit of a Duck" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.87)
  - "The Pleasures of Naturalist" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.88)
  - "Nature with Closed Doors" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.89)
  - "The Old Ice-Flood" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.90)
  - "Memories of a Pre-Civil War Farm" — EBK transcript (?), undated (Folder 62.91)
  - Atlantic Monthly — Full Issue, Feb 1859 (Folder 62.92)
  - Atlantic Monthly — Full Issue, with JB's annotated, Apr 1862 (Folder 62.93)
  - Atlantic Monthly — Full Issue, with JB's annotated, Jan 1863 (Folder 62.94)
  - Atlantic Monthly — Full Issue, with JB's annotated, Apr 1863 (Folder 62.95)
  - Atlantic Monthly — Full Issue, Sep 1864 (Folder 62.96)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles on war, 1914-1915, 1920 (Folder 65.11 (Oversize))
  - Lists of essay titles (Folder 62.97)
  - Covers and title pages of published poems and articles, (photocopies) (Folder 62.98)
- SERIES IV. CORRESPONDENCE: OUTGOING, 1857-1921
  - To Elizabeth Burroughs [daughter of Julian, Elizabeth Burroughs Kelley]
    - Nov 1919, (1 letter) (Folder 11.6)
  - To Emily Burroughs [wife of Julian]
    - 25 June 1911, (1 letter) (Folder 11.7)
    - 23 Aug 1912, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.8)
  - To Julian Burroughs
    - 1891-1896, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 11.9)
    - June-July 1897, (2 letters, 3 annotated, 1 postcard) (Folder 11.10)
    - 30 Sep 1897, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.11)
    - 16 Oct 1897, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.12)
    - 27 Oct - 11 Nov 1897, (1 letter, 2 postcards, 2 annotated) (Folder 11.13)
    - 7 Nov 1897, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.14)
    - 17 Nov 1897, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.15)
    - 29 Nov - 5 Dec 1897, (1 letter, transcript, 2 postcards, 2 annotated) (Folder 11.16)
    - 10-17 Dec 1897, 19 Jan 1898, (1 letter, 3 postcards 2 annotated) (Folder 11.17)
    - Jan 1898, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 11.18)
    - Feb-Mar 1898, (2 letters, 2 postcards, 3 annotated) (Folder 11.19)
    - 2 Mar 1898, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 11.20)
    - 4 Mar 1898, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 11.21)
    - 8-26 Mar 1898, (12 letters, 2 postcards, 4 annotated) (Folder 11.22)
    - Apr 1898, (1 letter, 1 postcard, 2 annotated) (Folder 11.23)
    - 2-11 May 1898, (3 letters, 3 annotated, 1 enclosure) (Folder 11.24)
    - 17-28 May 1898, (3 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 11.25)
    - June 1898, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 11.26)
    - Sep 1998, (1 postcard, 1 letter, 2 annotated) (Folder 12.1)
    - Oct 1898, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 12.2)
    - Nov 1898 11 Jan 1899, (2 letters, 2 postcards, 3 annotated) (Folder 12.3)
    - Jan 1899, (1 letter, 2 postcards, 2 annotated) (Folder 12.4)
    - Feb 1899, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 12.5)
    - Mar 1899, (2 postcards, 3 letters 4 annotated) (Folder 12.6)
    - Apr 1899, (3 letters, 3 postcards, 5 annotated) (Folder 12.7)
    - 3-17 May 1899, (1 letter, 2 postcards, 3 annotated) (Folder 12.8)
    - 20-31 May 1899, (1 letter, 3 postcards, 4 annotated, 1 enclosure) (Folder 12.9)
    - June 1899, (3 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 12.10)
    - July 1899, (2 letters, 1 photocopy, 2 annotated) (Folder 12.11)
    - 5 Oct 1899, (1 letter w/ photocopy, transcript, annotated) (Folder 12.12)
    - 11 Oct 1899, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 12.13)
    - Nov-Dec 1899, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 12.14)
    - 9 Jan 1900, (1 letter with transcript, annotated) (Folder 12.15)
    - 20 Jan 1900, (1 letter, 1 enclosure, 1 annotated) (Folder 12.16)
    - Feb 1900, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 12.17)
    - Mar 1900, (2 letters, 2 postcards, 3 annotated) (Folder 12.18)
    - Apr 1900, (1 postcard, 2 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 12.19)
    - May 1900, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 12.20)
    - June 1900, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 12.21)
    - Aug 1900, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.1)
    - Oct 1900, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 13.2)
    - Nov 1900- Jan 1901, (1 postcard, 2 letters, 1 enclosure, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.3)
    - 14-20 Feb 1901, (1 postcard, 2 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.4)
    - 26-28 Feb 1901, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.5)
    - Mar 1901, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.6)
    - Apr 1901, (3 letters, 2 postcards, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.7)
    - May 1901, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 1 annotated) (Folder 13.8)
    - June 1901, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.9)
    - Sep 1901, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 13.10)
    - Oct 1901, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 13.11)
    - Jan 1902, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.12)
    - July-Oct 1902, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.13)
    - Jan-Feb 1903, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.14)
    - 1-6 Apr 1903, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.15)
    - 11-22 Apr 1903, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.16)
    - May-July 1903, (3 letters, 3 annotated, 1 enclosure) (Folder 13.17)
    - Sep-Dec 1903, (3 letters, 1 enclosure, 3 annotated) (Folder 13.18)
    - 1904, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.19)
    - 1905, (3 letters, 1 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.20)
    - Feb 1906, (3 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 13.21)
    - July-Aug 1906, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 13.22)
    - Jan 1907, (1 letter, 1 photocopy, 1 annotated) (Folder 13.23)
    - Feb 1907, (3 letters, 1 photocopy, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.1)
    - Mar 1907, (4 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.2)
    - May-Dec 1907, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.3)
    - 6 Feb 1908, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 14.4)
    - 11 Feb 1908, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 14.5)
    - 18 Feb 1908, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 14.6)
    - 21 Feb 1908, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 14.7)
    - 1-14 Mar 1908, (3 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 14.8)
    - 25 Mar 1908, (1 letter, transcript, annotated) (Folder 14.9)
    - 26 Mar 1908, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 14.10)
    - May-July 1908, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.11)
    - Aug-Sep 1908, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 14.12)
    - Feb 1909, (1 letter, 1 postcard, 2 annotated) (Folder 14.13)
    - 3-11 Mar 1909, (3 postcard, 1 letter, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.14)
    - 12-24 Mar1909, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 14.15)
    - Apr 1909, (2 postcards, 1 letter, 1 photocopy, 4 annotated) (Folder 14.16)
    - May 1909, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.17)
    - June 1909, (1 letter, 3 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 14.18)
    - Sep 1909, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 14.19)
    - Jan 1910, (1 postcard, 1 annotated) (Folder 14.20)
    - July 1910, (4 letters, 1 postcard, 5 annotated) (Folder 14.21)
    - Aug 1910, (4 letters, 1 postcard, 5 annotated) (Folder 14.22)
    - Sep 1910, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 14.23)